Another area of the Web that we can monitor is our search analytics.
关于网络 还有一个关键领域需要监测 也就是搜索分析
Search analytics help you understand your organic search,
搜索分析可以帮你了解你的自然搜索流量情况
but they also can reveal opportunities around what you'll be doing with your paid search.
同时 也可以帮你挖掘一些付费搜索的优化机会
When we think about search analytics,
说到搜索分析
we can primarily use them to identify performance on particular search topics.
它的主要目的就是帮助你了解某个搜索话题的表现
We can use this in many different ways.
使用搜索分析 有很多种方式
For starters, we can identify which topics are driving a lot of our search traffic.
对于初学者 我们可以用搜索分析来判定哪些话题给我们产生了大量的搜索流量
We can see where we rank on various keywords.
我们可以看到对于不同的关键词 我们的排名是多少
We can also see what terms are popular for our brand.
也可以看到对于我们的品牌 哪些词语很常用
Now, we can use this data to identify competitive datasets.
如今 我们已经可以用搜索数据来判定行业竞争者的情况了
So we can start looking at what are we ranking for,
我们可以看看自己的排名情况
and what are our competitors ranking for.
再比较竞争者的排名情况
But as we look at this even deeper,
再深入一些的话
we can start to identify trends such as what people are most searching for.
我们也可以通过搜索分析来看看大家都在搜索什么
This can give us insights into the type of content that we could be creating.
这可以帮助我们追热点
Now in addition, we also have the ability to use all of
除此之外 我们也可以用这些信息来
this information to start selecting terms that we can use for our paid advertising.
筛选可以用于付费广告的词语文本
If we know that people are searching primarily on a specific topic,
如果我们已知大众都在搜索某个特定话题
now we can drive that both in our organic efforts as well as our paid efforts.
我们就可以将之用于自然流量渠道和付费流量渠道
Let's talk about the top tools.
介绍下行业领先工具
One of the first tools in the space is Google Trends.
首先是 Google Trends
This tool provides the ability to easily
Google Trends 可以帮助我们很容易就找到
identify the most popular search trends along with the ability
哪些是热搜话题
to quickly and easily search and explore what consumers
同时也让我们可以根据客户在 Google 搜索里输入的信息
are interested in based on what they're typing into Google.
从而快速、便捷地判定出他们会对什么感兴趣
You'll find this at trends.google.com.
网址：trends.google.com
Now, when you get into this tool,
进入工具后
you'll find that you have the ability to look at
你会发现你可以比较某些特定词的搜索情况
particular terms and compare how they're performing to other terms.
与其他词语的情况
Perhaps I want to identify whether removing a red wine stain from carpet,
比如 可以看到“如何处理地毯上的红酒酒渍”是否会比
is more or less popular than removing a grape juice stain from carpet.
“如何处理地毯上的葡萄汁水渍”的搜索次数更多 还是更少
This could influence what article I'd want
如果我经营地毯清洗服务
to write if I owned a carpet cleaning business.
这会影响我如何写一篇营销软文
You can also see how these concepts perform regionally and you'll also see
你也可以看到搜索根据地区的分布情况
what concepts are related or trending in association with those keywords.
以及与这些关键词语相关有哪些概念或者热搜
Now YouTube also has a similar trends tool and
YouTube 有一个类似的工具
that exists at youtube-trends.blogspot.com.
网址：youtube-trends.blogspot.com
Same idea, you can identify trending topics,
功能基本相同 你可以发现有哪些热搜话题、
trending videos, see what content is most popular and what content is most viewed.
热搜视频、哪些内容最受欢迎、哪些内容有最高的浏览量
This can help you in deciding where you want to participate in
这些信息可以帮助你决定是否要追热点
conversations or the types of videos that you might want to create.
或者创作什么类型的视频内容
Now, as we go deeper into our analytics efforts,
再深入一些
we can look at Google AdWords.
我们就会用到 Google AdWords
Now primarily we think of Google AdWords as a tool to run promotions,
Google AdWords 通常对于人们来说是一个付费推广工具
but within it are very helpful tools around keywords.
但它同时也是提供关键词搜索表现的强大工具
With these tools we can look at the popular keyword searches,
我们可以看到有哪些热搜关键词
identify the volume of those searches and see how
它们的搜索量是多少
competitive the landscape is for those keywords.
它们的竞价情况有多激烈
Another tool I really like is SEMrush.
SEMrush 是我很喜欢的另一个工具
I use this tool a lot in my organic research.
我经常用它来分析自然搜索流量
SEMrush allows you to look at all sorts of search data.
通过 SEMrush 你可以看到各种搜索数据
You can identify a particular keyword and see how popular that keyword is.
比如 某个关键词及其热搜程度
You can also see who's buying ads on that keyword,
有哪些公司在为这个关键词相关的付费广告而竞价
and it will even allow you to see the actual ads that are being displayed,
你甚至可以看到真实展现的广告
which allows you to look at the ad text that people are using so
以及这些广告都用了什么样的词语
you can begin to influence the types of ads that you want to run.
以便你决定是否也采用同样类型的广告或者不同类型的
It also allows you to do a competitive analysis.
你也可以用它做行业竞争对手分析
You can even track keywords that you're hoping to gain traffic for.
如果你想通过某些关键词导流 也可以跟踪这些关键词的表现
As you begin to think about the content that you want to run,
一旦你要开始思考用什么样的宣传内容
you'll have the ability to look at related keywords.
你就要开始看有哪些相关的关键词了
Additionally, you can use it to identify related keywords which is
另外 你也可以用这个工具来找到哪些相关的关键词
helpful in finding the wide space for new ideas to generate content.
可以给新想法很大的发挥空间 从而产生出更多的内容
As you can see, some tools are helpful not just to
所以 你也看到了 有一些工具不但可以帮助
evaluate and report on metrics but also to
衡量和汇报指标 同时也可以
identify and research concepts surrounding
发现和研究消费市场的热搜、趋势
the marketing and help influence decisions about your marketing campaigns,
从而影响你的推广活动
your content, and so on.
你的内容创作 等等